Dru Lang

1320 Lewisville Vienna Road Lewisville, NC 27023 336-575-3816 drulang@gmail.com http://drulang.com

Objective

To further my professional experience and knowledge of full stack application development by finding a challenging environment that is conducive to learning, collaborating, and always striving to find the best solution as an individual and team. Automation, Linux, web development, mobile app development and NoSQL are of great interest to me. I continually work on these skills at home through personal projects and by studying.

Technical Summary

Current Languages Python, Objective-C, SQL, Javascript

Previous Languages Java, C#, Perl, PHP

Software Vim, Eclipse, Subversion, Git, Mercurial, Vagrant, VirtualBox,

Oracle SQL Developer, Xcode 5, Chrome Developer Tools, VMware vSphere, Wireshark, Jenkins, GraphicsMagick, MySQL Workbench, VMWare Player

Frameworks Bootstrap, Flask, jQuery, Turbo Gears, SQL Alchemy, Selenium, Sphinx, Chart.js

DatabaseMySQL, Oracle, SQL Server, SQLite, RedisSystemsCentOS 6, Ubuntu 10, Ubuntu 12, OSX

Education

Appalachian State University; Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, May 2010

Work Experience

Orcatec, October 2013 - Present

Winston Salem, NC

Software Developer

- Maintain the document viewing feature
 - Added support for handling different file types (i.e. eml and msg file types)
 - Refactored large portions of the code to be sane
 - Fixed numerous bugs and wrote regression tests for them
 - Added various features such as zooming, rotation, and automatic user preference saving
- Fix and maintain the bulk document PDF rendering feature
 - This was a completely broken feature a client needed to be fixed quickly
 - Drastically improved the interface and underlying architecture for this feature in a timely manner
 - Refactored large amounts of the codebase to be more reliable and fixed numerous bugs
 - Added a dashboard to prevent user confusion on the state of a bulk print job
 - Shows a user's available downloads
 - Progress reporting for bulk rendering jobs
 - Ability to sort documents based on arbitrary metadata (I.e standardized date, docid)
 - Gained client and project manager's trust in feature
- Removed old document processing system
 - This involved massive scrubbing of entire codebase from installation scripts to user interface
 - Was successfully removed without breaking any existing features
- Wrote extensive test coverage using Selenium test framework
 - Often called upon to debug random failures in existing tests
- Troubleshoot production system issues

- Involves sifting through enormous log files, finding the error, reproducing locally and then creating a fix with regression testing
- Fix and fix the resource issues caused by GraphicsMagick and OpenOffice
- Became fairly proficient at reading and comprehending another developer's code

WhoFedThem.com, August 2014-present

Winston-Salem, NC

Founder and Lead Engineer

- Engineered, from the ground-up, an iOS app that allows households to keep in-sync with their pets' daily activities
 - 300 downloads with 80 homes registered all over the world
- Continually develop, test, and market the iOS app and REST API backend
- Developed REST API backend
 - Written in Python 2.6 with Flask and Flask-Restful framework
 - API has two versions
 - An extensive migration was needed to update database to version 2
 - Wrote integration test framework along with integration tests
 - Test framework creates and destroys fresh test environments
 - Designed normalized relational database
 - Entire API is documented with Sphinx
 - Wrote installation and setup scripts to allow easy setup
- Developed web landing page
- Designed and developed web admin platform to monitor activity
 - Used Chart.js to create charts that show daily activity
 - Use Google Maps API to see where homes are being created
- Designed and developed the iOS app
 - Utilizes REST API mentioned above
 - Frameworks used: Store Kit, Core Data and Core Location
 - Offers In-App purchases
 - Released a major update to utilize version 2 of the REST API
 - Familiar with the Apple release process
- Setup, administer, and network production, backup, monitoring and staging servers
 - Servers run CentOS 6.5
 - Production server
 - Houses the web landing page, REST API, and MySQL service
 - Staging/Backup server
 - Fully functional staging site that houses all of the services the production server does
 - Cron jobs provide database and filesystem offsite backups every 5 minutes over SSH
 - Nagios Monitoring Service
 - Production and Staging servers run the Nagios agent
- Gained an appreciation of the amount of non-technical work necessary to launch a product

Truliant Federal Credit Union, June 2010 – October 2013 Application Developer I, February 2012 – October 2013

Winston Salem, NC

- -Write Python programs to solve automation and business needs
 - -20 jobs; functionality including file handling, SSH, SFTP, and HTTP scripting
 - -Brought significant automation improvements to System Operations team
- -Write ad-hoc Python programs to solve immediate business needs
 - -Solutions include file processing/parsing/manipulation and bringing multiple data sources together; Oracle, SQL Server, CSV extracts

- -Wrote script to reserve 300 organizations in Core to save a business unit from doing manually through the use of Python, Oracle PL/SQL and the Core XML API
- -Wrote business-loan payment processor to post scheduled multi-thousand dollar payments
 - -Written in Python 2.7 with OOP principles
 - -Used third party SOAP WebServices, the Core XML API and raw sockets to handle TCP/IP communication with Core architecture
 - -Multithreaded application to significantly reduce processing time
 - -High profile project that was delivered on time and a huge success
- -Wrote web application to allow a non-technical department control a mission critical batch schedule
 - -Written using Python 2.7, Flask, Bootstrap, jQuery, Javascript
 - -Tied directly into the UC4's Application Manager database to provide synchronization for the various parts of the batch schedule

System Operations Specialist, June 2010 – February 2012

- -Maintained and monitored production batch schedule
 - -Rotated on-call schedule
 - -Responsible for specialized batch and processes (month end, year end, patches, etc.)
- -Wrote Python and Perl programs to automate and solve business problems
- -Received "Rookie Award"
- -Key leader during core conversion
 - -Worked heavily in batch implementation
 - -Led install, documentation, and training of UC4's Application Manager

BreyerFest Charity Horseshow, 2010-present

Greensboro, NC

Volunteer Developer

- -Responsible for creating a web application to help the manager maintain and do research on
- ~150 entrants and ~6000 horses
- -Primary features include:
 - Maintaining hundreds of show results organized into three sections
 - Managing user and horse profile pages
 - Searching for people/horses
- Written using standard LAMP stack
- Designed normalized relational database
- Reduced manager's workload from 72 hours to 8 hours

RateVail.com, December 2013-January 2014

Winston-Salem, NC

Founder and Lead Developer

- Created a website where people can anonymously rate and browse various shops in the Vail ski resort
- Each shop has a profile page where users can see ratings from RateVail and Google Places reviews
- Users do not have to create a profile to rate shops which is a fairly different approach to review sites
- Written with Python 2.7, Flask, Bootstrap and jQuery
- Site combines our user reviews with Google Places reviews and eventually Yelp's
 - Wrote batch job to pull places from Google Places API, format the data and store locally
 - Wrote batch job to pull reviews from Google Places API, format the data and store locally
- Designed normalized relational database
- Developed an admin page to maintain shop profiles as well as see daily activity